Finding Aid for Ben East papers, 1935-1980
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ben East papers
1935-1980
East, Ben.
0744 Aa 2
Ben East was a prominent Michigan outdoorsman and outdoor writer. The bulk of his career was spent as a writer and editor for Outdoor Life, a nationally distributed outdoors magazine. Additionally, he wrote for a number of Michigan-based newspapers and publications, and was a prominent Michigan conservationist.
13 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Materials were donated to the library by David and Kay Richey (donor no. 9852 ) in January 30, 2007.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Ben East (1898-1990) grew up hunting and fishing on his family's farm outside of Holly, Michigan, but didn't began his career as an outdoor writer until his mid-20s when he began selling short stories to magazines and local newspapers such as the Detroit News. The quality of his freelance work led to a permanent, full-time position establishing and editing the outdoor page of the Grand Rapids Press in 1926. He spent the next twenty years working for the newspaper and became a well-known and well-respected writer and lecturer. In 1946 he was honored with the invitation to present a talk to the National Geographic Society.
East continued to write freelance magazine stories during his tenure at the Grand Rapids Press, and in 1946 he was invited to joint the editorial staff of Outdoor Life, a nationally distributed outdoors magazine. He worked as a writer, field editor, and senior field editor during the almost thirty years he was employed by the magazine. The bulk of East's editorial work involved creating monthly regional inserts to be included in Outdoor Life subscriptions sent to the Great Lakes states. These inserts gave localized accounts of where to find good hunting and fishing, as well as outlined environmental threats to local rivers, lakes, and forests.
Though East was a long-standing and well regarded editor, his true gift was as a writer. East wrote and ghostwrote hundreds of stories for Outdoor Life until, and even after, his retirement in 1972. He earned the nickname the 'dean of outdoor writers' in recognition of his long career and his commitment to mentoring the aspiring writers who worked under and with him. He not only gained the respect of other writers, but the entire sporting community. He worked closely with hunters and sportsmen across the country to capture their stories and publish them under their own names. Many of the stories in this collection are attributed to other writers, but were in fact authored by East. In addition to his magazine and newspaper writing, East authored a number of books, notably of adventure stories, though he also published a novel and The Ben East Hunting Book--a comprehensive how-to book.
Though Ben East is most remembered as a writer he was also an early and important conservationist. He was deeply committed to preserving Michigan's natural beauty and was instrumental in gaining State Park status for both Tahquamenon Falls and the Porcupine Mountains. He also played a major role in securing Isle Royale as a National Park. He was involved in a number of conservation organizations and won the Michigan United Conservation Clubs Conservation Award in 1971 as well the Michigan Environmental Award and formal recognition by the Michigan state legislature, both in 1973.
The Ben East papers contain material dating from as early as 1935 and spanning the next 45 years of his career as an outdoorsman, writer, and conservationist with the bulk of the materials focusing on his career as an outdoor writer and editor. The collection is divided into five series: Editorial Copy, Personal Papers, Photographs, Publications, and Topical Files.
Subjects:
East, Ben.; Conservation of natural resources--Michigan.; Fishing--Michigan.; Hunting--Michigan.; Game and game birds.; Journalism, Outdoor.; Outdoor life.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
East, Ben.; Recreational fishing.; Hunting.; State parks & reserves--Michigan.; Game & game birds.; Pictured Rocks (Mich.); Tahquamenon Falls State Park (Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Editorial Copy
  The Editorial Copy series contains pre-print version of columns, articles, and stories for a number of different publications. The series is divided into subseries according to which publication the article originally appeared in, including the Detroit News, the Michigan Outdoor Almanac, and columns written for Outdoor Life. The largest subseries contains the editorial copy for the Outdoor Life regional inserts Mr. East edited throughout his career at the magazine. This subseries spans 19 years, from 1961-1978, though there are many chronological gaps in this subseries. The Editorial Copy series focuses on Mr. East's regular editorial duties such as recurring columns and assignments; feature articles for Outdoor Life are located in the Topical Files series and arranged by the subject matter of the article.
  - Detroit News-Nature's Corner
    - 1950-1953 (Box 1)
    - 1962-1965 (Box 1)
    - 1968-1970 (Box 1)
    - 1971 (Box 1)
    - 1972 (Box 1)
    - 1973 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Outdoor Almanac
    - September-December, 1978 (Box 1)
    - January-July, 1979 (Box 1)
    - August-December, 1979 (Box 1)
    - January-April, 1980 (Box 1)
    - May-December, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Outdoor Life Regional Inserts
    - January-May, 1961 (Box 1)
    - October, 1965 (Box 1)
    - 1968 (Box 1)
    - January-December, 1969, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - January-December, 1970, 7 folders (Box 1)
    - January-December, 1971, 5 folders (Box 1)
    - January-December, 1972, 12 folders (Box 1)
    - January-December, 1973, 12 folders (Box 2)
    - Regional Features (Box 2)
    - August-December, 1975, 5 folders (Box 2)
    - January-December 1976, 12 folders (Box 2)
    - Regional Inserts, 1977 (Box 2)
    - January-December, 1978, 12 folders (Box 2)
    - Policy Matters (Box 2)
  - Outdoor Life Columns
    - Bicentennial, 1975 (Box 2)
    - Roundup, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Roundup, 1975 (Box 2)
    - What's On Your Mind
      - 1964 (Box 2)
      - 1965 (Box 2)
      - 1971 (Box 2)
      - 1975 (Box 2)
  - Various Magazine Files
    - Articles, 1947-1958 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1947 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1947-1965 (Box 2)
- Personal Papers
  The Personal Papers section contains Ben East's personal correspondence, as well as files about awards and recognition that he received for his work.
  - Personal Correspondence
    - Bill Rae, 1958-1970 (Box 3)
    - Carl T. Johnson, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Chuck Kilburn, 1959-1971 (Box 3)
    - Frank Heidelbauer, 1955-1971 (Box 3)
  - Professional Recognition
    - John Fry, 1975-1977 (Box 3)
    - Various Correspondence, 1938-1970 (Box 3)
    - Michigan Environmental Awards, 1973 (Box 3)
    - Michigan United Conservation Clubs Award, 1971 (Box 3)
    - Newspaper Profiles (Box 3)
    - Rank of Colonel, 1953 (Box 3)
    - Various (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Notes on Photography (Box 3)
    - Political Support of W.H. Loutit, 1940-1941 (Box 3)
- Photographs
  The Photographs series contains files of photographic material in several forms including prints, negatives, slides, and clippings of 16mm filmstrips. Many of these photographs were included in Outdoor Life and are of professional quality. This series contains files that were exclusively photographic; photographic material that was integrated into files also containing print material in Mr. East's topical files remain in those files and that material is distributed throughout the collection.
  - Catfish, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Fire (effect on trees) (Box 3)
  - Fishing, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Pheasant, 1945 (Box 3)
  - Isle Royale (Box 3)
  - Kentucky (Box 3)
  - Kentucky Jump Fishing (Box 3)
  - Kentucky Junior Clubs (Box 3)
  - Lake Superior, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Laurel (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous/Identified (Box 3)
  - Porcupine Mountains (Box 3)
  - Safari (Box 3)
  - Stream Improvement (Box 3)
  - Stream Killers (Box 3)
  - Tahquamenon Falls (Box 3)
  - Upland Plover (Box 3)
  - Woodchuck (Box 3)
- Publications
  Ben East's full-length books are included in the Publications series of the collection. This series included these books, as well as files pertaining to their publishing or copyright. The collection does not contain a full catalog of East's books, but has a representative sample, including The Ben East Hunting Book and several editions in multiple languages of the Reader's Digest containing a condensed version of his book Silence of the North.
  - Bear Book file, 1975-1978 (Box 4)
  - Ben East Hunting Book file, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Book of Adventure file, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Forward to Bill Rae Book, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Ghostwriting Interview, 1978 (Box 4)
  - The Last Eagle file, 1974 (Box 4)
  - This Was the North file, 1973-1976 (Box 4)
  - Silence of the North movie rights, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Streamside Conservation Handbook file, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Survival Series file, 1978-1981 (Box 4)
  - The Ben East Hunting Book (Box 4)
  - Outdoor Life Book of Narrow Escapes (Box 4)
  - Outdoor Life Book of Survival (Box 4)
  - The Silence of the North (Box 4)
  - Reader's Digest Silence of the North
    - Italian language version (Box 4)
    - German language version (Box 4)
    - Danish language version (Box 4)
- Topical Files
  The largest and most extensive series in the collection is Ben East's Topical Files. Mr. East kept reference files on many types of plants and animals he encountered in his work as an outdoor writer, and included in these reference files any stories he had written on a particular topic. These Topical Files are divided into seven subseries: Adventure Stories, Birds, Conservation, Fish and Fishing, Mammals and Game Animals, Michigan Places, and Miscellaneous. These files contain numerous clippings as well as some of Ben East's best writing, both under his name and stories that he ghostwrote which appear under the names of his associates. The Michigan Places subseries includes a great deal of correspondence and other material relating to his efforts to dedicate Michigan's wilderness as state and national parks.
  - Adventure Stories
    - African Hunt, 1955 (Box 5)
    - Africa Story
      - 1950 (Box 5)
      - 1970 (Box 5)
    - Al Goerg Story, 1967 (Box 5)
    - Alaska Story
      - 1961 (Box 5)
      - 1964 (Box 5)
      - 1974 (Box 5)
      - 1978 (Box 5)
    - "An Old Warden Remembers", 1973 (Box 5)
    - British Columbia, 1962 (Box 5)
    - Broadback River Ordeal, 1979 (Box 5)
    - Canoe Story, 1979 (Box 5)
    - "Death Walked the Duck Marsh", 1965 (Box 5)
    - "Forty Day Ordeal", 1954 (Box 5)
    - Gamefishing, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Game Warden Story, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Hair Raisers, 1974 (Box 5)
    - Himes Drowning, 1977 (Box 5)
    - Humptulips Story, 1976 (Box 5)
    - James Bay Trip, 1937 (Box 5)
    - Jarden Canoe Trip, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Lake Michigan Shipwreck, 1958 (Box 5)
    - "The Long Move", 1963 (Box 5)
    - Lost for Trout, 1961 (Box 5)
    - Nanook of Shugliak, 1940 (Box 5)
    - Narrow Escape Stories, 1948 (Box 5)
    - "Night Death Prowled the Ice", 1969 (Box 5)
    - Night Without Fire, 1953 (Box 5)
    - Outdoor Life Girl, 1972 (Box 5)
    - "Ping Foster's Appendix", 1952 (Box 5)
    - Rainy Lake Trip, 1961 (Box 5)
    - Safari Story
      - 1956 (Box 5)
      - 1960 (Box 5)
    - "Search for a Boy", 1958 (Box 5)
    - "Summer in the Ice", 1954 (Box 5)
    - "Ten Terrible Days", 1961 (Box 5)
    - "Terror in the Surf", 1965 (Box 5)
    - "They Watched fro Ravens", 1963 (Box 5)
    - Tracking Dog Story, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Birds
    - Birds, general (Box 6)
    - Albatross (Box 6)
    - Audubon Society of Michigan (Box 6)
    - Auk (Box 6)
    - Birdhouses (Box 6)
    - Birds of Prey (Box 6)
    - Bittern (Box 6)
    - Buzzard (Box 6)
    - Ducks
      - Ducks (Box 6)
      - Duck Blinds (Box 6)
      - Duck Decoys (Box 6)
      - Duck Story, 1947 (Box 6)
      - Duck Story, 1951 (Box 6)
      - Duck Story, 1956 (Box 6)
      - Duck Story, 1977 (Box 6)
      - Duck Hunting Story "Crazy Little Fools", 1953 (Box 6)
      - Duck Story-Kankakee Story, 1947 (Box 6)
      - Ducks-Mallards (Box 6)
      - Duck Migration Corridors (Box 6)
      - Duck Stamp Sales, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Eagles
      - Bald and Golden (Box 6)
      - Eagle Feather Trade (Box 6)
      - Eagle Story, 1970 (Box 6)
    - Egret (Box 6)
    - Falconry (Box 6)
    - Feathers (Box 6)
    - Federal Cases (Box 6)
    - Flight Speeds (Box 6)
    - Geese
      - 1946-1969 (Box 6)
      - For Regional Report (Box 6)
      - Canada Geese Profile, 1975 (Box 6)
      - Hunt at Horseshoe Lake, 1954 (Box 6)
      - Hunt at James Bay, 1945 (Box 6)
      - Hunt at James Bay, 1951 (Box 6)
      - Trapping (Box 6)
    - Grouse (Box 6)
    - Grouse Article on Bill King (Box 6)
    - Grouse, Sharptail (Box 6)
    - Grouse, Spruce (Box 6)
    - Jacksnipe, 1953-1954 (Box 6)
    - Jays (Box 6)
    - Kirtland Warbler (Box 6)
    - Magpie (Box 6)
    - Martin-Purple (Box 6)
    - Nighthawk (Box 6)
    - Owl (Box 6)
    - Owl-Snowy (Box 6)
    - Meadowlark (Box 6)
    - Parakeets (Box 6)
    - Pheasants (Box 6)
    - Pheasant Hunting
      - 1955 (Box 6)
      - 1958 (Box 6)
      - 1967 (Box 6)
      - 1979 (Box 6)
    - Passenger Pigeon (Box 6)
    - Passenger Pigeon Story, 1975 (Box 6)
    - Prairie Chicken (Box 6)
    - Quail (Box 6)
    - Robins (Box 6)
    - Turkey (Box 6)
    - Whippoorwill (Box 6)
    - Wookcock (Box 6)
  - Conservation
    - Alaska
      - 1941-1970 (Box 7)
      - Guide Story, 1967 (Box 7)
      - Oil Pipeline, 1972 (Box 7)
      - 1976 (Box 7)
      - Violation Story, 1970 (Box 7)
      - Violation Story, Responses (Box 7)
    - Articles, 1970 (Box 7)
    - Cache River
      - 1972 (Box 7)
      - 1975-1977 (Box 7)
    - Channelization
      - 1970 (Box 7)
      - 1972-1974 (Box 7)
    - Endangered Species Story, 1974 (Box 7)
    - Grand Canyon, 1966 (Box 7)
    - Gunnison River Dam, 1959 (Box 7)
    - James Bay dam, 1972 (Box 7)
    - Kodiak Refuge, 1971 (Box 7)
    - Len Hall Profile, 1952 (Box 7)
    - Logging, 1970 (Box 7)
    - Michigan United Conservation Clubs (MUCC), 1966-1979 (Box 7)
    - Minnesota Award Story, 1952 (Box 7)
    - Ohio River Channelization, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Ohio River Work, 1975-1978 (Box 7)
    - Outdoor Nation, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Pesticides (Box 7)
    - Pesticide Story, 1969 (Box 7)
    - PCBs in Lake Michigan (Box 7)
    - Strip Mining (Box 7)
    - Strip Mining, 1966-1967 (Box 7)
    - Walter Hastings Profile, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Fish and Fishing
    - Fish, general (Box 8)
    - Alewife (Box 8)
    - Algoma Story (Box 8)
    - Bait (Box 8)
    - Bass
      - Bass (Box 8)
      - Fishing, 1948 (Box 8)
      - Fishing (Helin), 1959 (Box 8)
      - Fishing, 1961 (Box 8)
      - Fishing, 1962 (Box 8)
      - Fishing, 1963 (Box 8)
      - Fishing, 1964 (Box 8)
      - Fishing in the Great Lakes, 1964 (Box 8)
      - Fishing, 1965 (Box 8)
      - Fishing, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Bluegill (Box 8)
    - Bowfin (Box 8)
    - Bullhead (Box 8)
    - Carp (Box 8)
    - Catfish
      - Catfish (Box 8)
      - 1955 (Box 8)
      - 1965 (Box 8)
    - Charr, Arctic (Box 8)
    - Eels (Box 8)
    - Fileting Fish (Box 8)
    - "Fishing Close to Home", 1964 (Box 8)
    - Fishing Knots (Box 8)
    - Fishing Story, 1967 (Box 8)
    - Fly Fishing (Box 8)
    - Gar (Box 8)
    - Ice Fishing (Box 8)
    - Insect Food (Box 8)
    - Isle Royale Fishing, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Kentucky Jig Fishing (Box 8)
    - Kentucky Jump Fishing (Box 8)
    - Lake Saint Clair Fishing (Box 8)
    - Lake Superior Story, 1951 (Box 8)
    - Lampreys (Box 8)
    - Minnows (Box 8)
    - Musky Story
      - 1952 (Box 8)
      - 1961 (Box 8)
      - 1967 (Box 8)
      - Fishing in Ohio, 1972 (Box 8)
    - Paddlefish (Box 8)
    - Panfish Story, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Perch Story (Box 8)
    - Pike
      - Pike (Box 8)
      - Fishing Methods, 1959 (Box 8)
      - Story, 1979 (Box 8)
    - Records (Box 8)
    - Salmon Profiles, 1968 (Box 8)
    - Smoking (Box 8)
    - Spearing (Box 8)
    - Trout
      - Brook (Box 8)
      - Book Chapter, 1975 (Box 8)
      - Fishing Story, 1951 (Box 8)
      - Rainbow Trout Record, 1957 (Box 8)
  - Mammals and Game Animals
    - Antelope (Box 9)
    - Antelope Story, 1969 (Box 9)
    - Armadillo (Box 9)
    - Bears
      - Bears (Box 9)
      - "Alaska Gave us Everything,", Undated (Box 9)
      - "All the Bear I Needed,", 1977 (Box 9)
      - Bear Attack in Colorado, 1971 (Box 9)
      - "Bears are Unpredictable,", 1948 (Box 9)
      - "The Bears that Came to Supper,", 1961 (Box 9)
      - Bear and Spray Paint, 1979 (Box 9)
      - Bear Trapping Project, 1958 (Box 9)
      - "Big Bear of the Cedar Hells,", 1973 (Box 9)
      - "Big Kodiak Bear Fight,", 1964 (Box 9)
      - "The Camera Hunter's Greatest Game,", 1973 (Box 9)
      - Child Killing, 1973 (Box 9)
      - Chuck Oakley Story, 1979 (Box 9)
      - Connie King Story, 1968 (Box 9)
      - "Crackdown on Bear Guides,", 1968 (Box 9)
      - "Death for a Dog Killer,", 1957 (Box 9)
      - "Death in the Night,", 1962 (Box 9)
      - "Foot Race With a Grizzly,", 1955 (Box 9)
      - "The Greatest Hunting of All,", 1966 (Box 9)
      - "The Grim Reaper Has Beady Eyes,", 1969 (Box 9)
      - "A Grizzly Got My Goat,", 1948 (Box 9)
      - "The Guide a Grizzly Scalped,", 1966 (Box 9)
      - "Hunt Against Odds,", 1962 (Box 9)
      - "I Stopped a Brown Bear With a Handgun,", 1952 (Box 9)
      - "The Jaws of a Bear,", 1968 (Box 9)
      - "Moose-Hunting Grizzly,", 1974 (Box 9)
      - "Powder Keg in Black Fur,", 1979 (Box 9)
      - Robert Stevens Story, 1976 (Box 9)
      - Untitled Bear Story, 1970 (Box 9)
      - "You Go, I Stay,", 1960 (Box 9)
    - Bears
      - Polar Bears
        - Polar Bears, 1958 (Box 9)
        - "Bear That Broke a Jinx,", 1966 (Box 9)
        - "Death on Ice,", 1959 (Box 9)
        - "Great Hunt on Ice,", 1965 (Box 9)
        - "Polar Bears are Getting the Needle,", 1968 (Box 9)
        - "Polar Bears with Set Guns,", 1970 (Box 9)
        - "White Dynamite, Short Fuse,", 1962 (Box 9)
    - Beaver (Box 10)
    - Bison (Box 10)
    - Bobcats
      - General (Box 10)
      - Stories and Material (Box 10)
      - 1957 (Box 10)
      - 1964 (Box 10)
      - 1965 (Box 10)
      - 1967 (Box 10)
      - 1970 (Box 10)
      - Information for Regional Insert, 1973 (Box 10)
    - Buffalo Story, 1965 (Box 10)
    - Caribou (Box 10)
    - Cats of North America (Box 10)
    - Chipmunks (Box 10)
    - Dogs
      - Pack Dog Story, 1964 (Box 10)
      - Joe the woodcock dog (Box 10)
    - Deer
      - "Best Deer I Ever Had,", 1966 (Box 10)
      - "The Buck that Lived 22 Years,", 1972 (Box 10)
      - "Buck Fever,", 1974 (Box 10)
      - "Buck with a Bow,", 1955 (Box 10)
      - "Bucks on a Budget,", 1951 (Box 10)
      - Deer Hunt Montana, 1954 (Box 10)
      - Deer Hunting Photographs (Box 10)
      - Doe Hunting in Michigan, 1972 (Box 10)
      - Doe Shooting Book Chapter, 1974 (Box 10)
      - Deer Migration and Hunting in Colorado, 1954 (Box 10)
      - "Doe Quarrel,", 1974 (Box 10)
      - Deer-Dog Conflicts (Box 10)
      - "Double Hat Rack,", 1965 (Box 10)
      - Farmland Hunting, 1970-1972 (Box 10)
      - "The Fireplace Buck,", 1947 (Box 10)
      - "The Four Year Wait,", 1970 (Box 10)
      - "How to Bowhunt Deer,", 1959 (Box 10)
      - "How to Bowhunt Whitetails,", 1959 (Box 10)
      - "I Hunted a Record Head,", 1962 (Box 11)
      - "I Made My Deathbed,", 1964 (Box 11)
      - "More Rules for Whitetails,", 1958 (Box 11)
      - "The Mule Deer is Easier,", 1955 (Box 11)
      - My No. 4 Buck,", 1972 (Box 11)
      - Mystery of the Hinkley Head,", 1969 (Box 11)
      - "New Way to Hunt Deer" (Slingshot Story), 1969 (Box 11)
      - Porcupine Mountain Deer Hunt, 1947 (Box 11)
      - "Three's a Crowd,", 1958 (Box 11)
      - "Twenty Magic Minutes,", 1966 (Box 11)
      - "A Twig Can Do It,", 1956 (Box 11)
      - "Two Best Ways to Get a Deer,", 1963 (Box 11)
      - "Whitetails-Go Slow,", 1952 (Box 11)
      - "Wild Geese are a Good Omen,", 1951 (Box 11)
      - "You Make Your Own Luck,", 1977 (Box 11)
    - Elephants, 1966 (Box 11)
    - Elk
      - General (Box 11)
      - "How to Hunt Elk,", 1957 (Box 11)
      - "Wow! What a Wapiti,", 1966 (Box 11)
      - "Dream Hunt for Elk,", 1970 (Box 11)
      - "Elk on the Warpath,", 1965 (Box 11)
      - Elk Hunt in Custer Park, 1962 (Box 11)
      - "First and Best in 80 Years,", 1964 (Box 11)
      - Mercer Elk Story, 1959 (Box 11)
      - "Six Days in Icy Hell,", 1970 (Box 11)
    - Fox
      - Fox (Box 11)
      - Calling, 1955 (Box 11)
      - Calling, 1963 (Box 11)
      - Hunting, 1953 (Box 11)
      - Hunting, 1955 (Box 11)
      - Hunting, 1961 (Box 11)
      - Hunting, 1965 (Box 11)
    - Jackals, 1961 (Box 11)
    - Jackrabbits, 1952 (Box 11)
    - Lions
      - Lions (Box 12)
      - 1954 (Box 12)
      - Roy Murray, 1954 (Box 12)
      - 1961 (Box 12)
      - 1962 (Box 12)
      - African Lions, 1965 (Box 12)
      - Bowhunting, 1965 (Box 12)
      - 1965 (Box 12)
      - African Lion Story, 1969 (Box 12)
      - Mountain Lion Calling, 1972 (Box 12)
    - Lynx (Box 12)
    - Mice (Box 12)
    - Moose
      - Moose (Box 12)
      - "Blizzard Moose,", 1959 (Box 12)
      - Cal Olsen moose Story, 1962 (Box 12)
      - "First Moose-A Dream Come True,", 1951 (Box 12)
      - "I Never Want a Bigger Moose,", 1970 (Box 12)
      - Lowery Story, 1965 (Box 12)
      - Mech Moose Story, 1966 (Box 12)
      - "Moose at the Last Minute,", 1970 (Box 12)
      - "A Moose Hunter Needs Tracking Snow,", 1951 (Box 12)
      - "Moose in My Lap,", 1961 (Box 12)
      - Newfoundland Moose Story, 1968 (Box 12)
      - Ontario Moose Hunt, 1960 (Box 12)
      - "The Spring we Moved the Moose,", 1972 (Box 12)
      - Moose Tagging Story, 1960 (Box 12)
      - Moose Story, 1964 (Box 12)
      - "Moose Ten Feet Tall,", 1971 (Box 12)
      - Vass Moose Story, 1964 (Box 12)
    - Musk Ox
      - General (Box 12)
      - 1968 (Box 12)
      - 1969 (Box 12)
      - 1971 (Box 12)
    - Muskrat (Box 12)
    - Opossum (Box 12)
    - Otter (Box 12)
    - Porcupine (Box 12)
    - Rabbits
      - General (Box 12)
      - Cottontail (Box 12)
      - 1979 (Box 12)
      - Hunting, 1959 (Box 12)
      - Snowshoe Hunting, 1959 (Box 12)
      - Snowshoe Hunting, 1964 (Box 12)
      - "Rabbits are Big Game,", 1975 (Box 12)
    - Raccoon (Box 12)
    - Predators (Box 13)
    - Predator Calling (Box 13)
    - Sheep
      - Chadwick Ram Story, 1979 (Box 13)
      - Desert Sheep Story, 1970 (Box 13)
      - Sheep Story, 1947 (Box 13)
      - Sheep Story, 1964 (Box 13)
    - Squirrel (Box 13)
  - Michigan Places
    - Isle Royale
      - National Park, 1935-1974 (Box 13)
      - Fire, 1936 (Box 13)
      - 1946 (Box 13)
      - Winter Story, 1955 (Box 13)
      - 1969 (Box 13)
      - 1970 (Box 13)
      - 1979 (Box 13)
      - Backpacking, 1972 (Box 13)
    - Manistee River, 1963 (Box 13)
    - Pictured Rocks (Box 13)
    - Porcupine Mountain State Park, 1946-1978 (Box 13)
    - Rivers and Lakes (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Alligator (Box 13)
    - Animal Tracks (Box 13)
    - Anti-venom (Box 13)
    - Beaver Recipes (Box 13)
    - Fire Ant (Box 13)
    - Frogs (Box 13)
    - Gun Control (Box 13)
    - Handgun Control (Box 13)
    - Hellbender (Box 13)
    - Hibernation (Box 13)
    - Highway System, 1961 (Box 13)
    - Hunting
      - License Sales, 1947-1976 (Box 13)
      - Bowdoin Conference, 1976 (Box 13)
      - Defense of (Box 13)
      - Guns of August Responses, 1975 (Box 13)
    - Indian Foods (Box 13)
    - Indian Rights (Box 13)
    - Insects (Box 13)
    - Maine Story, 1968 (Box 13)
    - Map Story (Box 13)
    - Multiflora Rose (Box 13)
    - Mushrooms (Box 13)
    - Pest Control (Box 13)